Carissa Shum

778-387-2836 cwkshum.github.io carissa_shum@sfu.ca As a Vancouver based developer and designer, my goal is to create a positive user experience through the work I produce by combining my knowledge in coding and design. I aim to create meaningful applications ranging from the web to mobile that can exceed the needs of the intended users.

Design Skills

- Wireframing
- Prototyping
- Ideating
- Interface Design

Technical Skills

- HTML / CSS
- NA 601
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Premiere

- PHP
- MySQL
- Adobe Illustrator
- Android Studio

- C / C++
- Processing

JavaScript

- Adobe After Effects
- Figma

- Java
- Arduino
- Adobe InDesign
- Axure RP

Work Experience

March - June 2021

Web Design and Development Internship

SeeRem

- Created mockups and a prototype in a team of three using Figma for SeeRem's web application to be used as a reference during its development process.
- Restructured the existing website to better convey the SeeRem application to potential customers and coded the changes using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Successfully launched the SeeRem site using the Google Cloud Platform which resulted in positive recognition from the company's CEO.

Sept 2018 - Present

Dance Teacher

Panorama School of Dance

- Taught multiple ballet, jazz, and lyrical classes every week to children ranging from the age of three to eleven years old.
- Choreographed dance routines for the studio's yearly productions that showcased the abilities and talents of each dancer.
- Conducted weekly online dance classes which allowed students to continue dancing safely during the pandemic.

Jan 2018 - Present

Multimedia Designer

Panorama School of Dance

- Edited fourteen camp videos that were shared with the families which featured dance performances, highlights, and a photo slideshow using Adobe Premiere.
- Designed display slides for the waiting rooms to inform students and parents about current and upcoming events.
- Compiled images and formatted them to be projected onto the theatre's stage to be used as backdrops for two of the studio's yearly dance productions.



Volunteer Experience

Sept 2019 - Feb 2020

SIAT TechTeams Leader

Simon Fraser University

- Collaborated with three other student leaders to organize weekly sessions for first-year students to help them transition into university and to learn about the Interactive Arts and Technology program.
- Facilitated twelve workshop sessions that encouraged discussion among peers while assisting in the development of their design skills.
- Created presentations and activities that educated students on topics regarding design principles and web design.

Academic Projects

Mobile Application Feb - April 2021

VanCity Cycling - App Developer & UI/UX Designer

- Developed an Android cycling route planning app in a team of two in collaboration with CityStudio and the City of Vancouver to promote bike riding as a mode of transportation for novice cyclists.
- Designed the branding as well as the user interface of the application and coded the app's functionality using Java, which resulted in favourable feedback from the teaching team.
- Presented the completed application to the City of Vancouver's Transportation
 Division where the app received recognition for its friendly interface and
 various planning features that would benefit beginner cyclists by making
 biking in the city more convenient.

Web Application Sept - Dec 2020

Shoe Addiction - Front-end & Back-end Developer

- Worked in a team of three to make a fictional shoe store web application, focusing on the back-end handling of user requests to better understand the structure of present-day e-commerce sites.
- Implemented a database using MySQL to store a user's account information, retrieve product or user information, and allow for record updates for a fully developed web application.
- Coded the site using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for seamless user interaction, including the ability to filter product results, and PHP to process user and database information.

Education

2018 - Present

Simon Fraser University

BSc. in Interactive Arts and Technology

- Recipient of the SFU Undergraduate Scholars Entrance Scholarship
- President's and Dean's Honour Roll (2019-2021)